Register of the A. (Andrei) Siniavskii Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- SINTAKSIS FILE, 1968-1995 (Box 63)
  - Manuscripts submitted for publication. Arranged alphabetically by name of author.
    - Chilingarian, Sergei, "Naedine s V. V. Rozanovym," 1965. (Folder 82: 10)
    - Davydov, Oleg, miscellany, n.d. (Folder 82: 11)
    - Dolgopolov, Leonid, "Konets vsekh kontsov i nachalo vsekh nachal...," n.d. (Folder 82: 12)
    - Dombrovskii, Iurii, "V Sekretariat Soiuza Pisatelei," n.d. (Folder 82: 13)
    - Efimov, Igor, miscellany, 1991. (Folder 82: 14)
    - Epshtein, Mikhail, essays, n.d. (Folder 82: 15)
    - Erofeev, Viktor, "Mat'," 1990. (Folder 82: 16)
    - Etkind, Efim., See CORRESPONDENCE/Etkind, Efim, and SUBJECT FILE/Etkind, Efim
    - Fishtein, E., "Vzgliad na severo-vostok," 1985. (Folder 83: 1)
    - Fomin, Sergei, "Vozmozhny varianty," n.d. (Folder 83: 2)
    - Galperin, Iurii, "Russkii variant," n.d. (Folder 83: 3)
    - Gamaiun, ?, 1988. (Folder 83: 4)
      Typescript drafts
    - Garin, Aleksei, plays, 1990. (Folder 83: 5)
    - Genis, Aleksandr, essays, 1994-1995. (Folder 83: 6-7)
    - Gershuni, V., "Ideologi s bol'shoi dorogi," 1980 and "Superepus" with enclosed letter to Siniavskii, 1992. (Folder 83: 8)
    - Gil, Pinkhas, "Kak eto delalos' v Evrope," 1986. (Folder 83: 9)
    - Girshevich, Leonid, "Prais," 1987. (Box-folder 84: 1-2)
    - Glazov, Iurii, "Mar'ia Timofeevna v russkom soznanii," 1986. (Folder 84: 3)
    - Golomshtok, Igor', n.d.
      - "Masony" (Folder 84: 4)
      - "Al'bom." Layout for Russian version of Totalitarian Art (Folder 84: 5)
    - Golynko, Dmitrii, "Put'," 1987. (Folder 84: 6)
    - Gorbanevskii, Mikhail, "Kogda zazvonit kolokol?" 1990. (Folder 84: 7)
    - Gorchakov, Genrikh, "Odinatsatoe somnenie," 1990. (Folder 84: 8)
    - Gorenshtein, Fridrikh, short story, 1984. (Folder 84: 9)
    - Gorin, Igor', poetry, 1989. (Folder 84: 10)
    - Gorodinskii, Mikhail, short stories, 1991-1992. (Folder 84: 11)
    - Grois, Boris, miscellany, 1982. (Folder 84: 12)
    - Gunitskii, Anatolii, "Do samykh vysot," 1989. (Box-folder 85: 1)
    - Guseinov, Arif, ed., "Poraznenie tseli: Moskva 21 sentiabria-12 dekabria, 1993 v materialakh pressy, radio, televideniia," 1994. (Folder 85: 2)
    - Iakhot, Iegoshua, essays, 1979. (Folder 85: 3)
    - Iakovlev, Sergei, "Chernaia pauza," n.d. (Folder 85: 4-6)
    - Ianov, Aleksandr, essays, 1980., See also SUBJECT FILE/Solzhenitsyn, Aleksandr/ Writings about (Folder 85: 7-8)
      Typescript.
    - Il'iazd (Il'ia Zdanovich) (Box 86)
      - "Parizhach'i," n.d. (Folder 86: 1)
      - Miscellany, 1919-1945. (Folder 86: 2-3)
        Photocopy of printed copies
    - Il'in, Sergei, short stories and essays, 1988. (Folder 86: 4-6)
    - Inozemtsev, Vladislav, essay, n.d. (Folder 86: 7)
    - Itselev, Leonid.
      - "Protokoly moskovskikh mudretsov," n.d. (Folder 86: 8)
      - "Grezy pchely trudovoi: Stranitsy zhizni Aleksandry Kollontai: Roman-kitch," 1985 (Folder 86: 9)
    - Iulis, Oleg, miscellany, n.d. (Box-folder 87: 1)
    - Ivanitskii, Vladimir, "O lunnom i solnechnom zatseplenii slov," n.d. (Folder 87: 2)
    - Ivask, Iurii, "Zavoevanie Meksiki," 1970. (Folder 87: 3)
    - Kaganskaia, Maia, "Shutovskoi khorovod," n.d. (Folder 87: 4)
    - Kandel', Feliks, "Ne proshlo I zhizni," 1977-1991. (Folder 87: 5)
    - Katsenelingboigen, Aron, essay, 1988. (Folder 87: 6)
    - Kenzheev, Bakhyt.
      - "Plato," 1988-1991 (Folder 87: 7)
      - "Ivan Bezuglov," 1992 (Folder 87: 8)
    - Khanan, Vladimir, "Russkaia istoriia v svete khristianskogo opyta," 1989. (Folder 87: 9)
    - Khazanov, Boris, "Velichie sovetskoi literatury," 1982. (Folder 87: 10)
    - Kibirov, Timur, poetry, 1988-1990. (Folder 87: 11)
    - Klenov, Andrei, "Tri strany," 1977. (Box-folder 88: 1)
    - Klimov, Vladimir, essays, 1991. (Folder 88: 2)
    - Komarova, Olga, "Sorokovoi den'," n.d. (Folder 88: 3)
    - Kononov, Nikolai, poetry, and fiction ("Pokhorony kuznechika" and "V trezvom ume"), n.d. (Folder 88: 4-5)
    - Konstantinovskii, Il'ia.
      - "Belki v kolese," n.d. (Folder 88: 6-7)
      - "Kak svecha ot svechi," n.d. (Folder 88: 8-9)
      - "Proshchai Edem," 1992 (Box-folder 89: 1-3)
    - Kopelev, Lev, short stories, 1972. (Folder 89: 4)
    - Kostylev, Valerii, poetry. (Folder 89: 5)
    - Kozhevnikov, Petr, n.d.
      - "Khudozhnik" (Folder 89: 6)
      - "Ostrov" (Folder 89: 7-8)
    - Kozovoi, Vadim, "Sfinks," n.d. (Folder 89: 9-10)
      Typescript. Also includes material related to collection to aid Kozovoi
    - Krakhmal'nikova, Zoia, "Blagovest'," 1974. (Folder 89: 11)
    - Krasin, Viktor, essay, 1975. (Folder 89: 12)
    - Kruglikov, Vasilii, "V pautine kompiliativnogo smysla," n.d. (Folder 89: 13)
    - Kruzhkov, Grigorii, typescript essay and printed copy of Cherepakha, 1991 (Box-folder 90: 1)
    - Kuchaev, Andrei, "Blesk glaz," 1989. (Folder 90: 2)
    - Kundera, Milan, "Kniga smekha I zabveniia," 1981. (Folder 90: 3)
    - Kuraev, Mikhail, "Blok - ada," 1994. (Folder 90: 4)
    - Kuraptseva, Natal'ia. Correspondence, typescripts of poetry, and printed copy of Vremianka, 1994 (Folder 90: 5)
    - Kurliandskii, A., "Belobrysen'kaia," 1990. (Folder 90: 6)
    - Kustanovich, Konstantin, "Ne lukom edinym...," 1981. (Folder 90: 7)
    - Kuz'mina, Liudmilla, "Avgusteishii poet," 1992. (Folder 90: 8)
    - Leibgor, "Venetsianets," 1992. (Folder 90: 9)
    - Lenskii, Mark, "Chelovek iz dzhaza," 1995. (Folder 90: 10)
    - Levitin-Krasnov, Anatolii., See also SINTAKSIS FILE/Correspondence and PHOTOGRAPHS/Levitin-Krasnov, Aleksandr
      - Biographical material. Clippings, 1975-1983 (Folder 90: 11)
      - Writings.
        - General (Folder 90: 12)
        - "Emigratsiia: Khozhdenie za tri moria," n.d.
          - "Rim" (Folder 90: 13)
          - "München" (Folder 90: 14)
        - Speech delivered at Radio Liberty symposium, 1975 (Folder 90: 15)
        - "Moskovskii Sbornik: Religioznye stat'i 1956-1959," 1987. (Box-folder 91: 1-2)
          Includes photocopies of articles from Zhurnal Moskovskoi Patriarkhii, 1956-1959
        - "Pisatel' i poet," 1988 (Folder 91: 3)
        - "Rossiia nachala XX veka glazami dvukh pisatelei," 1988 (Folder 91: 4)
        - Open letter to Mikhail Gorbachev, 1989 (Folder 91: 5)
        - "Zemlia dybom," 1989 (Folder 91: 6)
    - Levykin, Viacheslav, "Cherv' nostalgii," 1992. (Folder 91: 7)
      Typescript. Includes "Chetvertaia kniga," 1989. Printed copy
    - Limonov, Eduard., See also SUBJECT FILE/Limonov, Eduard
      Typescripts.
      - "Amerikanskie kanikuly," n.d.
        - Version 1 (Folder 91: 8)
        - Version 2 (Folder 91: 9)
      - "Distiplinarnyi sanatorii," n.d. (Box-folder 92: 1-2)
      - "Kar'ery etikh dam," n.d. (Folder 92: 3)
      - "Moskva maiskaia," n.d. (Folder 92: 4-6)
      - "On the Wild Side," n.d. (Folder 92: 7)
      - "Pochemu mne nepriiatno, kogda menia nazyvaiut dissidentom," n.d. (Folder 92: 8)
      - "Istoriia ego slugi," 1983 (Folder 92: 9)
    - Linetskii, Vadim, short stories and articles, n.d., See also BIOGRAPHICAL FILE/Articles about Siniavskii (Box-folder 93: 1-2)
    - L'vov, Arkadii, "Zheltoe i chernoe," n.d. (Folder 93: 3)
    - Maksudov, Sergei., See Babenyshev, A.
    - Maliukova, Larisa, short stories, n.d. (Folder 93: 4)
    - Margolina, Irina, short stories, n.d. (Folder 93: 5)
    - Margolina, Sofiia, "Mirovozrenie Osipa Mandel'shtama," 1986. (Folder 93: 6)
    - Mechev, Sergei, miscellaneous biographical material and untitled writing re underground church, n.d. (Folder 93: 7)
      Corrected proofs
    - Mezhibovskii, Leonid, short stories, 1989-1990. (Folder 93: 8)
    - Mijailov, Mijailo, "Bezotvetsvenost' i nedomyslie," 1981. (Folder 93: 9)
    - Mnatsakanova (Netzkowa), Elena. Miscellany, 1981-1983. (Box-folder 94: 1)
      Typescript and photocopies of drawings
    - Naumov, Aleksandr, poetry, n.d. (Folder 94: 2)
    - Nekrasov, Vsevolod, poetry, 1990. (Folder 94: 3)
    - Nikitin, Ivan, "Posylalis' s neba zvezdy," 1980. (Folder 94: 4)
      Typescript samizdat
    - Nikolaev, Aleksei, poetry, n.d. (Folder 94: 5)
    - Nivat, Georges, "Estetika simvolizma," n.d. (Folder 94: 6)
    - Nosik, Boris, "Komnata zdorov'ia" and miscellaneous poetry, 1987. (Folder 94: 7)
    - Novikov, V., "Sovremennye problemy," 1992. (Folder 94: 8)
    - Pachmus, Temira, "Iz arkhiva A. A. Gershel'mana," n.d. (Folder 94: 9)
    - Petrov, Nikolai, "Zapiski trotskista," 1986-1987., See also SUBJECT FILE/Solzhenitsyn, Aleksandr/Writings about (Folder 94: 10-11)
    - Petrov, Nikolai, "Zapiski trotskista," 1986-1987., See also SUBJECT FILE/Solzhenitsyn, Aleksandr/Writings about (Box-folder 95: 1)
    - Petrushevskaia, Liudmila, writings, 1988-1989. (Folder 95: 2-3)
      Typescript and photocopies
    - Piatigorskii, A., esssay, n.d. (Folder 95: 4)
    - Pomerants, Igor', essays, 1979-1990. (Folder 95: 5-6)
      Holographs and typescripts
    - Popovskii, Mark, "Litsa I maski," n.d. (Folder 95: 7)
    - Porokhnia, Leonid, "Den' kogda priedet tsyrk," n.d. (Folder 95: 8)
    - Proffer, Karl, "Dvoinaia zhizn' Vladimira Nabokova," n.d. (Folder 95: 9)
    - Prokhvatilov, Valerii, "Pochta po krugu," 1990. (Folder 95: 10)
    - Purin, Aleksei, "Apokrofy Feognida," 1994-1995. (Folder 96: 1)
    - Razumovskii, Oleg, "Mezhdudvukh," 1988. (Folder 96: 2)
    - Reformatskaia, M., "Rasskazhy pro diadiu Sashu" and "S A. A. Akhmatovoi v myzee V. V. Maiakovskogo," 1968. (Folder 96: 3)
    - Reiman, Mikhail
      - "Dokumenty konuna stalinshchiny," n.d. (Folder 96: 4-5)
      - "Lenin i bor'ba za 'leninskoe nasledstvo," n.d. (Folder 96: 6)
      - "Rozhdenie stalinizma," 1978 (Folder 96: 7-8)
    - Roziner, Felix
      - "Zapiski palomnika," n.d. (Folder 96: 9)
      - "Kargopol'skie makovki," 1976. (Folder 96: 10)
        Typescript with photographic inserts
      - Temnyi dom, 1983. (Folder 96: 11)
    - Rudich, V., "Imperatorskii Rim i sovetskaia Rossiia," 1979. (Folder 96: 12)
    - Rzhevskii, Leonid, "Kommunizm: Eto molodost' mira," n.d. (Folder 96: 13)
    - Saed-Shakh, Anna, "Smert' pionerki," n.d. (Box-folder 97: 1)
      Typescript. Includes introduction by Evgenii Evtushenko
    - Samoilov, David, essays, n.d. (Folder 97: 2)
    - Sapgir, Kira, "Tkan' lzhi," n.d. (Folder 97: 3)
    - Savitskii, Dmitrii, poetry, "Dozhdlivoe leto v Parizhe," "Passé décomposé: Futur simple," and "Ploshchad' nesoglasiia," 1982. (Folder 97: 4-5)
    - Shchetinin, Georgii, "Iz zametok dlia sebia," 1972. (Folder 97: 6)
    - Shklovskii, Evgenii, "Posledniia liubov'," n.d. (Folder 97: 7)
    - Shubinskii, Valerii, short story and poetry, 1990. (Folder 97: 8)
    - Shul'man, Mikhail, "Nabokov," 1995. (Folder 97: 9)
    - Simis, Konstantin, "Strana kleptokratii," n.d. (Folder 97: 10)
    - Sokolov, Aleksandr, "Shkola dlia durakov," 1973. (Box-folder 98: 1)
    - Sorokin, Vladimir, "Serdtsa chetyrekh," 1991. (Folder 98: 2)
    - Spektor, Usher, "Babel' i Esenin," 1990-1991. (Folder 98: 3)
    - Sukonik, A., miscellany, 1975. (Folder 98: 4)
    - Svetov, Feliks, "Poslednie razgovory," n.d. (Folder 98: 5)
    - Tainin, Georgii, "Zhili byli babushka i vnuk," 1986. (Folder 98: 6)
    - Tarasov, Aleksandr, "Istoriia bednoi besedki," 1970, "Braider i Chad-o-vich," 1996, and "Podonok," 1997. (Folder 98: 7)
    - Temin, Gennadii, writings re Soviet camps., See also PHOTOGRAPHS/Temin, Gennadii
      - General. (Folder 98: 8)
        Typescripts, n.d.
      - Kolymskii detektiv, 1989, and Otdushina, 1990. (Folder 98: 9)
        Printed copies
    - Timofeev, Leonid, "Stikhi," n.d. (Folder 98: 10)
    - Toporov, Viktor, miscellany, 1993. (Folder 98: 11)
    - Ulitin, Petr, short stories, n.d. (Box-folder 99: 1)
    - Urusova, Marina, "Levaia pravaia gde storona," n.d. (Folder 99: 2)
    - Ushakova, Elena, poetry, 1989-1990. (Folder 99: 3)
      Typescript and clipping
    - Vail, Petr., See Genis, Aleksandr
    - Vedeniapin, Dmitrii, "Pokrov," 1990. (Folder 99: 4)
    - Vinogradov, Igor', "Lik' litso i lichina naroda," n.d. (Folder 99: 5)
    - Voinovich, Vladimir, "Fiktivnyi brak," n.d. (Folder 99: 6)
    - Volokhov, Mikhail, literary reviews, n.d. (Folder 99: 7)
    - Vozdvizhenskii, Viacheslav, "Bedstvie srednego vkusa, ili vygovor Borisu Pasternaku," 1988. (Folder 99: 8)
    - Zakharov, Vsevolod, "Razmyshleniia ob emigratsii," 1983. (Folder 99: 9)
    - Zhavoronkov, Gennadii, "Vremia samykh nevkusnykh iablok," and memoir of Ezhov's daughter, n.d. (Folder 99: 10)
    - Zholkovskii, Aleksandr
      - General, n.d. (Folder 99: 11)
      - "Dusha, dal' i tekhnologiia chuda," n.d. (Folder 99: 12)
        Typescript and galley proof
      - "Deux rencontres à la datcha," lecture for Colloque International Vladimir Maiakovski et l'Utopie du XX-ème Siècle, 1993. (Folder 99: 13)
    - Zil'berberg, Il'ia, "Pamiati Marka Morozova," n.d. (Folder 99: 14)
    - Zinik, Zinovii, "Mol'" and miscellaneous essays and fiction, 1984-1994. (Folder 99: 15)
    - Zinik, Zinovii, "Mol'" and miscellaneous essays and fiction, 1984-1994. (Box-folder 100: 1-2)
    - Zolotonosov, Mikhail, "Akhutokots-Akhum," n.d. (Folder 100: 3)
  - Reviews of Sintaksis in the French press, 1981 (Folder 100: 4)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1907-1999
  - "A" do "Ia." Miscellany, 1985-1985 (Folder 100: 5)
  - Akademiia garmonitelei. Miscellany, 1993-1995. (Folder 100: 6)
  - Amalrik, Andrei., See also PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Correspondence - Amalrik, Giuzel', n.d. (Folder 100: 7)
    - Interviews, 1977. (Folder 100: 8)
    - Material related to his book Rasputin: dokumental'naia povest'
      - Photocopies and notes on printed matter re Rasputin from the Hoover Institution Library and Archives, 1912-1975 (Folder 100: 9-11)
      - Photocopies and notes on printed matter re Rasputin from the Hoover Institution Library and Archives, 1912-1975 (Box-folder 101: 1-5)
      - Photocopies and notes on printed matter re Rasputin from the Hoover Institution Library and Archives, 1912-1975 (Box-folder 102: 1-2)
      - Typescript drafts with holograph corrections, n.d.
        - Version 1 (Folder 102: 3-5)
        - Version 1 (Box-folder 103: 1)
        - Version 2 (Folder 103: 2-3)
        - Version 3 (Folder 103: 4)
      - Page proofs, n.d. (Folder 103: 5-7)
  - Anti-semitism, 1989. (Box-folder 104: 1)
    Miscellany
  - Aucouturier, Michel
    - Newspaper clippings re arrests and trials of Soviet dissidents, 1967-1968., See also BIOGRAPHICAL FILE/Articles about Andrei Siniavskii (Folder 104: 2)
    - Writings. Drafts of articles about Andrei Siniavskii and Iulii Daniel for Le Monde, 1965-1966. (Folder 104: 3)
  - Belotserkovskii, Vadim
    - General. Correspondence, public appeals, and newspaper clippings related to his dismissal from Radio Liberty and subsequent trial, 1985-1986., See also SUBJECT FILE/Djilas, Milovan and Mijailov, Mijailo, and SINTAKSIS FILE/Correspondence/Belotserkovskii, Vadim (Folder 104: 4)
    - Correspondence, 1976-1986 (Folder 104: 5)
    - Writings.
      - General, 1977-1986 (Folder 104: 6-8)
      - Letters to the editor and open letters, n.d. (Folder 104: 9)
        Includes letter on his behalf
      - Questionnaire created by Belotserkovskii for Suchasnist magazine re nationality problem in the U.S.S.R., 1979 (Folder 104: 10)
      - Radio scripts for Radio Liberty, 1978-1979., See also Radio Liberty/Transcripts of radio programs (Folder 104: 11)
  - Booker Russian Novel Prize, 1992-1996., See also PHOTOGRAPHS/Siniavskii, Andrei
    - General. (Folder 104: 12)
      Includes material re judges and contestants. Typescript and printed matter
    - Correspondence with Andrei Siniavskii. (Folder 104: 13)
  - Brigada po izucheniiu i propagande tvorchestva V. V. Maiakovskogo. Material from its archive., See also OVERSIZE FILE/Posters
    - Announcement for poetry contest, 1949 (Folder 104: 14)
    - Letter from Vasilii Kamenskii to Artem Bromberg (Folder 104: 15)
    - Writings of Artem Bromberg, "Brigada Maiakovskogo" and "Slovo Maiakovskogo zhivet," n.d. (Folder 104: 16)
  - British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC). Miscellany, 1996 (Folder 104: 17)
  - Brodsky, Josef. Programs for public events featuring Brodsky, 1985 (Box-folder 105: 1)
  - Chernov, Andrei, "Progulki po pushkinskomu domu," 1999. (Folder 105: 2)
  - Daniel, Aleksandr. Miscellany, 1972-1989 (Folder 105: 3)
  - Daniel, Iulii., See also Rappoport, Natalia
    - Correspondence re Daniel, including material about or from him transmitted through other correspondents, 1976 (Folder 105: 4)
    - Medical report, 1984. (Folder 105: 5)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1970 (Folder 105: 6)
    - Poetry, n.d. (Folder 105: 7)
    - Writings, "Zaivlenie Iuliia Danielia," 1975. (Folder 105: 8)
  - Djilas, Milovan, "Demokraticheskaia no i russkaia Rossiia," 1978. (Folder 105: 9)
    Typescript and clipping of published version. Includes "Odgovori na pitanja G. V. Belotserkovskogo" and letter to Vadim Belotserkovskii, 1979
  - Dragosh, Nikolai, "Politicheskaia avtobiografiia," n.d. (Folder 105: 10)
  - Eltsin, Boris. Script of television interview with Andrei Karaulov, n.d. (Folder 105: 11)
  - Eshche. Miscellany, 1994 (Folder 105: 12)
  - Etkind, Efim
    - General, 1975-1980 (Folder 105: 13)
    - Writings. (Folder 105: 14-15)
      Includes writings by others compiled by Etkind: "Dialog s Antisemitom," "Kul'tura i antikul'tura," "Moi drug zheleznyi," "Razgovory bezhentsev," "Taina smerti Borisa Poplavskogo," "80 let akademiku Likhachevu," 1986. Holograph and typescript
  - Filandrov, Vladimir. Writings, 1982. (Folder 105: 16)
  - Freidin, Gregory. Writings, 1991-1992. (Folder 105: 17)
  - Gershuni, Vladimir. Miscellany, 1992. (Folder 105: 18)
    Handwritten and printed matter
  - Ginsgurg, Aleksandr. Radio Liberty program dedicated to him, n.d. (Folder 105: 19)
  - Gladilin, Anatolii. Clippings, 1976 (Folder 105: 20)
  - Goldberg, Lev. Trial records, 1936-1956. (Folder 105: 21)
  - Golomshtok, Igor'. Clippings, 1953-1959 (Folder 105: 22)
  - Gorbanevskaia, Natalia. Miscellany, 1975-1995 (Folder 105: 23)
  - International Sakharov Committee and International Sakharov Hearings, 1975-1976., See also CORRESPONDENCE (Folder 105: 24)
    Printed matter.
  - Kataoka, Miiko., See OVERSIZE FILE/Lithographs
  - Kaverin, Veniamin. Letter to Nadezhda Mandel'shtam, 1973 (Folder 105: 25)
  - Konferentsiia demokraticheskikh dvizhenii i organizatsii strany, Leningrad, 1989. (Folder 105: 26)
  - Kozyrev, Andrei. Speech at the Sorbonne, n.d. (Folder 105: 27)
  - Ktorova, Alla. Miscellany, 1987 (Folder 105: 28)
  - Kublanovskii, Iurii. Untitled writing, n.d. (Folder 105: 29)
  - Kuznetsov, Vladimir, "Istoriia odnoi kompanii," 1995. (Folder 105: 30)
  - Lenin, Vladimir. Clippings from Soviet newspapers about his death, 1924 (Folder 105: 31)
  - Limonov, Eduard. Clippings, 1985-1992 (Box-folder 106: 1)
  - Maksimov, Vladimir
    - Clippings, 1975-1995 (Folder 106: 2)
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1982-1994 (Folder 106: 3)
      - Gorbachev, Mikhail, 1994 (Folder 106: 4)
    - Interviews, 1985-1994 (Folder 106: 5)
    - Obituaries, 1994-1995 (Folder 106: 6)
    - Open letters and letters to the editor re Kontinent and Maksimov, 1978-1979. (Folder 106: 7)
      Typescript. Includes letter of Vladimir Bukovskii
    - Writings
      - General, 1986-1994. (Folder 106: 8)
      - "Daiesh' rynok!" n.d. (Folder 106: 9)
      - "Istoriia odnoi kapituliatsii," n.d. (Folder 106: 10)
      - "Mozhesh' vyiti na ploshchad'?" n.d. (Folder 106: 11)
      - "Neperenosimaia legkost' zastoia," n.d. (Folder 106: 12)
      - "Sdacha i gibel' russkoi intelligentsii," n.d. (Folder 106: 13)
      - "Skol'ko kolokolu zvonit'?" n.d. (Folder 106: 14)
  - Mandel'shtam, Osip. Announcements for centennial celebrations, 1991 (Folder 106: 15)
  - Mandel'shtamovskoe Obshchestvo. Miscellany, 1992 (Folder 106: 16)
  - Maramzin, Vladimir. Writings, 1975-1976 (Folder 106: 17)
  - Markish, Simon. Untitled writing, n.d. (Folder 106: 18)
  - Medvedev, Roy and Zhores. Miscellany, 1974-1978 (Folder 106: 19)
  - Memorial. Clipping, "O chesti i dostoinstve 'Memoriala'," 1992 (Folder 106: 20)
  - Mijailov, Mijailo
    - Clippings, 1986-1987 (Folder 106: 21)
    - Letter to the editor, New York Times, 1987. (Folder 106: 22)
    - Writings, "Vozvrashchenie Velikogo Inkvizitora," 1980. (Folder 106: 23)
  - Mogutin, Iaroslav, 1994-1995. (Folder 106: 24)
    Newspaper clippings of articles by and about him
  - Molchanov, Gennadii, "Sovetskii kontslager," 1991. (Folder 106: 25)
    Samizdat
  - Morozova-Utenkova, Ekaterina, Stranitsy zhizni: Vospominaniia o V. I. Tsvetaevoi i A. S. Efron, 1996 (Folder 106: 26)
  - Nekrasov, Viktor, "V. P. Nekrasov," n.d. (Folder 106: 27)
  - Novyi mir. A. Strelianyi, public dicussion at MGU, 1987. (Folder 106: 28)
  - Old Believers. Pamphlets, 1973 (Folder 106: 29)
  - Orthodox Eastern Church, Georgian, Sud'by gruzinskoi tserkvi, Moscow, 1907. (Box-folder 107: 1-4)
    Photocopy
  - Orthodox Eastern Church, Russian, "Tserkov', Kul'tura, Ideologiia." Samizdat re rennaissance of Russian Orthodox Church, 1980. (Folder 107: 5)
  - Pamiat'. Interview with Konstantin Smirnov-Ostashvili, n.d. (Folder 107: 6)
  - Petkevich, Tamara. Clippings, 1990-1998 (Folder 107: 7)
  - "Priroda i my" (St. Petersburg). Miscellany, n.d. (Folder 107: 8)
  - Radio Liberty
    - Bulletin by Iuliia Vishnevskaia, 1987 (Folder 107: 9)
    - Clippings about RFE/RL, 1986-1998 (Folder 107: 10)
    - Correspondence, 1994 (Folder 107: 11)
    - Program schedule, 1975 (Folder 107: 12)
    - Transcripts of radio programs
      - General
        - Undated (Folder 107: 13)
        - 1975-1976 (Folder 107: 14)
        - 1977
          - January-May (Folder 107: 15)
          - August-September (Box-folder 108: 1)
          - October-November (Folder 108: 2)
        - 1978-1991 (Folder 108: 3)
      - "Besedy Kuznetsova.", See also AUDIO-VISUAL FILE/Phonotapes/Kuznetsov, Anatolii
        - 1972-1973, Nos. 2-3, 11 (Folder 108: 4)
        - 1974
          - Nos. 44-50 (Folder 108: 5)
          - Nos. 51-59 (Folder 108: 6)
          - Nos. 60-69 (Folder 108: 7)
          - Nos. 71-79 (Folder 108: 8)
          - Nos. 80-87 (Folder 108: 9)
        - 1975 (Box 109)
          - Nos. 88-99 (Folder 109: 1)
          - Nos. 100-115 (Folder 109: 2)
          - Nos. 116-129 (Folder 109: 3)
        - 1976
          - Nos. 130-144 (Folder 109: 4)
          - Nos. 145-162 (Folder 109: 5)
        - 1977
          - Nos. 163-175 (Folder 109: 6)
          - Nos. 176-202 (Folder 109: 7)
      - "Besedy Vladimirova," Leonid Vladimirov
        - 1974 (Folder 109: 8)
        - 1975 (Box 110)
          - February-April (Folder 110: 1)
          - June-October (Folder 110: 2)
      - "Chelovek na zemle"
        - 1974 (Folder 110: 3)
        - 1975
          - January-February (Folder 110: 4)
          - March-May (Folder 110: 5)
          - June-December (Folder 110: 6)
        - 1976 (Folder 110: 7)
      - "Evreiskaia Kul'turno-obshchestvennaia zhizn'," 1975-1976 (Folder 110: 8)
      - "Kul'tura, sobytiia, liudi," 1977 (Box-folder 111: 1)
      - "Liudi i sud'by," 1970 (Folder 111: 2)
      - "O chem sporiat," 1976 (Folder 111: 3)
      - "Piat'desiat let tomu nazad"
        - 1974-1975 (Folder 111: 4)
        - 1976 (Folder 111: 5)
        - 1977 (Folder 111: 6)
      - "Prava cheloveka," 1975-1976 (Folder 111: 7)
      - "Radioseminar," 1976 (Folder 111: 8)
      - "Rossiia vchera, segodnia, zavtra," 1976-1984 (Folder 111: 9)
      - "Sovremennaia Velikobritaniia," David Floyd and Anatolii Kuznetsov, 1977 (Folder 111: 10)
      - "Svidetel'stvo protsesa" (Box-folder 112: 1)
      - "V mire knig" (Folder 112: 2)
  - Rappoport, Natalia. Writings, 1990. (Folder 112: 3)
  - Remizov, Aleksei. Letter to Bronislav Bronislavovich, 1949. (Folder 112: 4)
  - Russia (Federation) - Students. "Khartiia 95." (Folder 112: 5)
  - Samizdat
    - General
      - Ideologiia i byt v tvorchestve Chekhova, n.d. (Folder 112: 6)